Guide to the William Nicoson papers, 1954-2007
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
William Nicoson papers
1954-2007
C0164
George Mason University. Libraries. Special Collections & Archives
12.0 linear feet (25 boxes)
The William Nicoson papers contain material on Reston redevelopment, mostly promotional. The collection includes maps, charts, publications, slides, and newsclippings. The collection also includes information on federal housing agencies and documentation on new towns in the United States, France, Sweden, and the United Kingdom.
Nicoson, William
Access Restrictions
There are no access restrictions.
Acquisition Information
Donated by William Nicoson in multiple parts, first in 1992, then October 6, 1994, August 26, 1998 and the final donation was made on January 12, 1999.
Biographical Information
William Jarvie Nicoson (1932-2013) was born in Pittsburgh, Pennsylvania to Marion Jarvie and William McGarvey Nicoson. He attended Phillips Exeter Academy, Princeton University, and Harvard Law School. He spent his Junior Year of college at the Sorbonne in Paris, where he studied acting with the Director of the Comedie Francais. At Princeton, he was a member of the Army ROTC. He served as an officer in the U.S. Army in Germany for two years.
Nicoson's career began at the law firm of Sullivan & Cromwell. He worked in New York City and Paris practicing law before moving to Washington, D.C. in the 1960s.
In 1965 the Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD) was created as an executive cabinet-level agency. HUD's mission is to help promote affordable home ownership and community development. William Nicoson was the first Director of the New Community Assistance Program at HUD. The primary goal of this office was to help foster cooperation among all levels of government and private business, both non-profit and profit. He resigned from this position in 1972.
When he moved to Washington, D.C., from New York City, he moved to the then-new community of Reston, Virginia. Robert E. Simon, Jr. was the founder of Reston. Simon purchased the land with the proceeds from the sale of Carnegie Hall in New York City in 1961. Construction began in 1963 with the building of Lake Anne. Nicoson and Simon shared many interests in planned communities and taught a course together in New Community Planning at the New School in New York City.
Nicoson was very active in Reston community organizations and served on a number of boards and committees. He was one of the founders of the Reston Connection newspaper and he served as publisher and writer of a weekly column for five years. He also wrote a monthly column for the Reston Times. In 2002 he was given the "Best of Reston" award for his civic participation.
Scope and Content
The William Nicoson papers contain material on Reston redevelopment, mostly promotional. The collection includes maps, charts, publications, slides, and newsclippings. The collection also includes information on federal housing agencies and documentation on new towns in the United States, France, Sweden, and the United Kingdom.
Series one is titled Correspondence. The series contains different correspondence to and from William Nicoson. The correspondence covers a variety of topics such as the Interstate Land Development Company, Low-Income Households in New Towns, Chapel Hill Study and William Nicoson's personal correspondence. The series is dated from 1965 to 1980 and is contained in boxes 1 through 3.
Series two is titled Reston. The series includes information about the development on Reston, including the Reston Town Center, Lake Anne Elementary School and newsclippings from newspaper in Reston and outside of the area. The series is dated from 1960 to 1985 and is contained in boxes 3 through 5.
Series three is titled Federal. The information in this series is from federal programs and agencies including Congress about the development of new towns. The material covers a variety of topics such as U.S. Government Memorandum on Tax Reform Act from 1969, U.S. Senate Report on New Towns and Housing and Urban Development (HUD). The series is dated from 1960 to 1980 and is contained in boxes 5 through 8.
Series four is titled International. The series covers a variety of international new towns from France, Sweden, the United Kingdom and others, mostly European nations. Most of the information is brochures, maps and statistics from the international new towns. The series is dated from 1957 to 1979 and is contained in boxes 8 through 12.
Series five is titled Newsclippings. The articles in this collection are mostly from newspapers about different new towns both nationally and internationally. Also in the series are articles written by different people involved in new town development. The series is dated from 1960 to 1985 and is contained in boxes 12 through 14.
Series six is titled General Information. The information in this series covers a variety of topics such as Richmond Metropolitan Authority, Town and Country Planning Association and New Communities Development Handbook. Also included are booklets, advertisements, slides and maps. The series is dated from 1954 to 1999 and is contained in boxes 14 through 20.
Series seven is titled Newspaper Columns. This series consists of paper and digital files containing original drafts and research materials for newspaper columns written by William Nicoson that were originally published in the Reston Connection during the late 1990s and early 2000s. The series contains materials dating from 1982 to 2007 and comprises box 21 through 25.
Arrangement
Organized into six series.
Series 1: Correspondence, 1965-1980 (Boxes 1-3)
Series 2: Reston, 1960-1985 (Boxes 3-5)
Series 3: Federal, 1960-1980 (Boxes 5-8)
Series 4: International, 1957-1979 (Boxes 8-12)
Series 5: Newsclippings, 1960-1985 (Boxes 12-14)
Series 6: General Information, 1954-1999 (Boxes 14-20)
Series 7: Newspaper Columns, 1982-2007 (Boxes 21-25)
Related Material
The Special Collections and Archives also holds the Planned Community Archives and other personal papers and organizational records that document Reston, Virginia, and other planned communities.
Index Terms
Persons:
Nicoson, William.
Corporate Names:
United States. Dept. of Housing and Urban Development.; United States. Office of New Community Development Corporation.
Geographical Names:
Reston (Va.)
Subjects:
Housing--Virginia--Reston.; Planned communities--Virginia--Reston.
Contents List
- Series 1: Correspondence, 1965-1980; (2.5 boxes)
  The correspondence covers a variety of topics such as Interstate Land Development Company, Chapel Hill Study and William Nicoson's personal correspondence.
  - Grady Correspondence, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    323.30
  - Commuter Bus Service, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    324.01
  - Operations and Management Brand to Residents, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    323.41
  - Curriculum Vital and Memorandum on Painting Classes, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    323.42
  - U.S. Government Memorandum Low-Income Households in New Towns, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    327.17
  - Domestic Growth-Current President Memorandum and Budget, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    329.01
  - Memorandum Concerning European Tour, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    329.07
  - Housing and Urban Development (HUD) Correspondence, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
    329.09
  - Office of New Communities Development, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    329.11
  - Press Release by Ted A. Dienstfrey, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    329.14
  - Correspondence to Nicoson, Underhill, Koons and Interstate Land Development Company, Incorporated, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    329.17
  - Cedar Riverside, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    3332.09
  - Suggested Review Assignments for Interdepartmental Committee Members Concerning French Plans for the New Town of Vaudreuil, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    330.24
  - Towards a New Swedish Housing Policy: Directives for a Government Commission, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
    334.01
  - Remarks by Howard R. Moskof at the Columbia New Town In Town Conference, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 15)
    334.08
  - Ehr liehman Presentation, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    332.12
  - Report of U.S. Interagency Vaudreuill Project Group and Memoranda Associated with It, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    333.05
  - Legal Basis for SBA's Minority Enterprise Program by John A. Knebel, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    328.11
  - Conference, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    334.14
  - Conference, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    334.13
  - Handbook, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    420.2
  - Handbook Master, 1972 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    420.1
    - Letter: William J. Nicoson to Leonard Gordon, September 1, 1972; 1.
    - Letter: William J. Nicoson to Leonard Gordon, October 6, 1972; 2.
    - Letter: William J. Nicoson to Leonard Gordon, October 20, 1972; 3.
    - Letter: William J. Nicoson to Leonard Gordon, November 20, 1972; 4.
    - Letter: William J. Nicoson to Leonard Gordon, December 22, 1972; 5.
  - Personal Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    337.02
  - Personal Correspondence, 1972-1973 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    337.01
  - Academy for Contemporary Problems, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    1
  - Travel Abroad, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    336.06
  - Chapel Hill, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    338.02
  - Cornell Seminar, 1974 (Box 2, Folder 7)
    338.03
  - Growth Policy, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 8)
    339.05
  - Lake Forest Address, Wharton, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 9)
    339.06
  - Princeton Lecture, G.W. Panel, 1975 (Box 2, Folder 10)
    339.07
  - Covington and Burling, 1976 (Box 2, Folder 11)
    338.05
  - Chapel Hill Study, 1977 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    338.04
  - Report of "Maryland Planning and Zoning Law", 1978 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    3
  - Property Advising Group-London David Hall, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    340.11
  - New Release Major Saint John Development Announced, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    340.12
  - Athens, 1978 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    340.14
  - Housing Subcommittee Correspondence, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    341.02
  - Taylor Woodraw Property Company Limited, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    341.03
  - Correspondence from January 4, 1979 (Box 3, Folder 7)
    341.06
  - Office of Technology Assessment, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 8)
    2
  - Utah Lecture, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 9)
    341.12
  - Mark Winkler Management, Incorporated-Correspondence, 1980 (Box 3, Folder 10)
    341.14
- Series 2: Reston, 1960-1985; (2 boxes)
  The series includes information about the development on Reston, including the Reston Town Center and newsclippings.
  - Common Grand Coffee House-Menu, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 11)
    322.13
  - Reston, Virginia, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 12)
    322.09
  - Living...Reston Style, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 13)
    322.29
  - A Place Called Reston, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 14)
    322.27
  - Welcome to Lake Anna Elementary School, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 15)
    322.26
  - Reston Town Crier, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 16)
    324.09
  - Reston Town Center, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 17)
    324.17
  - Model Townhouses at Reston, Virginia, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 18)
    323.01
  - YWCA of Reston-Classes: Trimnastic and Beginning Bridge, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 19)
    323.03
  - Walking Tour of Lake Anne, 1960s (Box 3, Folder 20)
    323.04
  - The New Town Reston, Virginia Map (two copies), 1960s (Box 3, Folder 21)
    323.15
  - Industrial Property Guide-Reston Supplement, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    322.25
  - Washington New Neighbor, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    323.24
  - Waterview Cluster Association, Lake Anne Center and Homeowners, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    324.18
    - Waterview Cluster Association, May 17, 1966; 2.
    - To: All Members of the Waterview Cluster Association; From: Robert E. Simon, Jr., October 12, 1965; 1.
  - Reston Activities, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    323.07
  - Heron House Art Gallery Reston, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    323.08
  - Reston Offices, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    323.11
  - Information Pamphlet on Reston (2 copies), 1965 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    323.14
  - Builders of Individual Houses at Reston, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    323.27
  - Lake Anne Community Center-Tennis Club, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    323.28
  - Evelyn Davis Playhouse, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 31)
    323.29
  - Lake Anne village Center Opening, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 32)
    323.32
  - The Reston Letter, Volume 3, Number 3, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 33)
    323.31
  - Reston Executive Office Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 34)
    323.26
  - Reston Rental Manager, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 35)
    324.03
  - Lake Anne Center Lecture Series-Ticket, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 36)
    323.35
  - Reston Counts 1000 Residents and New Looks Like New Town by John b. Willmann, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 37)
    323.34
  - Lake Anne Center, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 38)
    323.33
  - Teenage meeting and Community Relations Department Concert and ARt Exhibit, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 39)
    323.38
  - Lake Anne Center Lecture Series, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 40)
    323.37
  - Urban Land, Volume 25, Number 2-February, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 41)
    323.39
  - News From Reston, February 10, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 42)
    323.43
  - Survey Announcement by William and Mary, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 43)
    323.44
  - The Reston Letter, Volume 4, Number 1-May 21, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 44)
    323.48
  - The Reston Letter, Volume 4, Number 2-May 21, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 45)
    323.49
  - Opening of Reston Community Center Travel Series-August 27, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 46)
    323.50
  - The Reston Letter, Volume 4, Number 3-May 21, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 47)
    323.47
  - The Reston Letter, Volume 4, Number 2-January, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 48)
    324.05
  - The Reston Music Center Season, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 49)
    324.04
  - Dedication of Lake Anne Elementary School-April 30, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 50)
    324.07
  - The Reston Chorale and Chamber Orchestra, 1967 (Box 3, Folder 51)
    323.23
  - Christmas Concert, The Reston Chorale, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 52)
    324.08
  - bulletin-Reston Community Association-April 1, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 53)
    324.13
  - The Nature Center-A Center for Environmental Management and Education-Spring, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 54)
    324.12
  - Gulf-The Organe Disc-March and April, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 55)
    324.11
  - Reston Community Association Newsletter, Volume 1, Number 2-January, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 56)
    324.10
  - the Environment Monthly, Reston is Alive and Well in Virginia-October, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 57)
    324.22
  - Bulletin-Reston Community Association, Incorporated-May 17, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 58)
    324.21
    - RCA Bullletin, May 17, 1969; 1.
  - Nature Newsletter, Volume 3, Number 4, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 59)
    324.20
  - Reston Spring Festival Chairmen, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 60)
    324.19
  - Trade Winds Travel, Incorporated, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 61)
    322.02
  - The Smith House at Reston, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 62)
    322.21
  - Realtor's Advertisement, 1970s (Box 3, Folder 63)
    322.20
  - Cedar Ridge Advertisement and Floor Plan (2 copies), 1970s (Box 3, Folder 64)
    322.19
  - The Goodman Houses at Reston-Advertisements, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 1)
    322.18
  - Reston at a Forest's Edge-New HOmes Priced From the Mid-Twenties, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 2)
    322.17
  - The Design House Reston-New Homes Tour Map, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 3)
    322.16
  - Reston Golf Course Map, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 4)
    322.15
  - Composite Plan and Prices Waterford Square, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 5)
    322.12
  - Greater Reston Arts Center (GRACE), 1970s (Box 4, Folder 6)
    322.11
  - The Fairway-Floor Plans, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 7)
    322.04
  - Golf Course Island Reston, Virginia Site and Floor Plan, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 8)
    322.03
  - Serendipity, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 9)
    322.44
  - A Community Great Decision Group-Lake Anne Community Center, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 10)
    322.43
  - Reston Center of VMFA, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 11)
    322.41
  - The Community and the Individual-Discussion Series, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 12)
    322.40
  - Reston Community Center, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 13)
    322.33
  - The Reston Commuter Bus Can Get You Into Washington Faster Than You Can Get There Yourself, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 14)
    322.32
  - Reston Development Plan, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 15)
    322.31
    - Reston Development Plan (Map), ca. 1980; 1.
  - Invitation to a F.F.R. Dedication Dance-May 2, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 16)
    322.30
  - Fellowship House-Lake Anne Village, Floor Plans, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 17)
    322.24
  - Reston, Virginia-Finished Models, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 18)
    322.23
  - Advertisement for Reston Schools, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 19)
    322.22
  - Southgate Square Information Packet, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 20)
    322.49
  - Reston: A Town That Helps Its People Cope with the Problems of Living in Times Like These, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 21)
    322.48
  - Waterview Cluster Dog Committee, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 22)
    322.47
  - Reston Players, Incorporated, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 23)
    322.46
  - Reston Geographic Society, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 24)
    325.04
  - Map of Reston, Virginia (Initial Development), 1970s (Box 4, Folder 25)
    323.05
  - Reston Community center Floor Plan and Site Plan, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 26)
    323.06
  - Grace More Than An Art Gallery, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 27)
    323.12
  - Summer Twilight Series Memorandum, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 28)
    323.13
  - Just Outside The Nation's Capital is One of the Best Neighborhoods in America, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 29)
    323.17
  - Reston Homeowners Association (RHOA) Pathways and Facilities Map, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 30)
    323.16
  - Reston Model Home Village-Homes By Different Builders, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 31)
    323.18
  - Map of Reston, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 32)
    323.21
  - The Reston Golf and Country Club, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 33)
    323.20
  - Gulf Reston to Build Low Income Housing, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 34)
    322.1
  - Reston Master Plan, 1970s (Box 4, Folder 35)
    322.42
  - This is a Commitment to the New Town Concept (Reston Community Association), 1970s (Box 4, Folder 36)
    322.50
  - Reston Area Community Center, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 37)
    324.36
    - Reston Area Community Center, ca. 1977; 1.
  - Gulf Oil Corporation, 1973 (Box 4, Folder 38)
    324.28
  - Reston Magazine, Volume 1-November, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 39)
    324.32
  - Reston Today-Reston Fact Sheet-Spring, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 40)
    324.30
    - Reston Today - Reston Fact Sheet Spring 1975, 1.
  - Reston Notice from the Postal SErvice, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 41)
    324.34
  - Raw, Raw, Reston Homeowners Association (RHOA), 1976 (Box 4, Folder 42)
    324.37
  - Booklets, 1976-1977 (Box 4, Folder 43)
    324.33
  - Meeting Your Own Best Friend-Lake Anne Community Center New Release, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 44)
    324.39
  - Dedication Access-May 21st, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 45)
    324.40
    - Dedication of ACCESS, May 21, 1977; 2.
  - 2nd Annual USE Membership Gourmet Dinner and Gala Evening-June 3, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 46)
    324.41
  - The Reston Area Community Center, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 47)
    324.38
  - Annual Champagne Art Auction to Benefit Grace Art Gallery-December 2, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    324.45
  - Reston Floor plans, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 49)
    322.28
  - Fairfax County Redevelopment and Housing Authority Annual Report, 1979-1980 (Box 4, Folder 50)
    324.49
  - Reston Facts and Figures, 1980s (Box 4, Folder 51)
    325.14
  - Harvard Law School Bulletin: "We've Heard About Reston and Columbia But What About Soul City, North Carolina?", 1980s (Box 4, Folder 52)
    332.03
  - Reston Film Festival, 1980s (Box 4, Folder 53)
    322.38
  - Poster-Reston Christmas, 1980s (Box 4, Folder 54)
    322.37
  - Restonian, 1980s (Box 4, Folder 55)
    322.36
  - Gulf Reston, Incorporated: Floor Plans at Vantage Hill, 1980s (Box 4, Folder 56)
    322.35
  - The Burlington Homes at Reston, Virginia, 1980s (Box 4, Folder 57)
    322.34
  - "Dracula"-Advertisement To See It, 1980s (Box 4, Folder 58)
    322.39
  - Reston-Washington Plaza, 1980s (Box 4, Folder 59)
    322.05
  - Reston-Quayside, 1980s (Box 4, Folder 60)
    322.06
  - Reston: A New Town for a New Kind of Life, 1980s (Box 4, Folder 61)
    322.08
  - Shop Reston Catalog, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 62)
    324.50
  - Lake Anne Village-Invitations to Visit New Model Homes, 1980 (Box 4, Folder 63)
    325.01
  - The Reston Garden Club and The Reston Community Center "Images", 1981 (Box 4, Folder 64)
    325.10
  - Coldwell Banker-Sunderbrian Townhouses, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 65)
    322.14
  - Lake Anne Village Price List, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 66)
    322.10
  - Reston-Lake Anne Village Center, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 67)
    322.07
  - Reston Advertisements, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 68)
    341.18
  - Reston Homeowners Association (RHOA) Architectural Board of Review, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 69)
    325.05
  - Organizations Attending Volunteers Leader's Conference-October 23, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 70)
    325.19
  - Volunteer Leaders' Conference-October 23, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 71)
    325.18
  - Great Reston Arts Center Newsletter, Volume 7, Number 4-August and September, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 72)
    325.16
  - Great Reston Arts Center, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 73)
    325.22
  - Reston Advertisements, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    341.19
  - Reston Neighborhoods, 1983-1984 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    325.23
  - Reston Anniversary, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    325.29
  - Reston Symposium: May 8-11, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    325.43
  - Reston 20th Anniversary Committee Correspondence: April 15, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    325.42
  - The Annual Juried Fine Arts Exhibition-The Greater Reston Arts Center: April 5-May 5, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    325.41
  - Reston Celebrates Youth Art Month and Reston's 20th Year: February 24-March 24, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    325.40
  - Reston 20th Anniversary Committee-Pamphlets: May 9, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    325.44
- Series 3: Federal, 1960-1980; (3 boxes)
  The information in this series is from Federal programs and agencies including Congress about the development of new towns. The material covers a variety of topics such as U.S. Senate Report on New Towns and Housing and Urban Development (HUD).
  - Toward a National Urban Land Policy by Robert C. Wood, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 9)
    327.03
  - Migration of Non-Whites-Source: U.S. Census Bureau, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 10)
    327.04
  - Improvement of Economic Structure, 1960s (Box 5, Folder 11)
    326.21
  - Urban Land Development Part IV: Harvard Business School, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    327.20
  - Comparative Listings of Selected Recommendations form the Douglas Commission and Kaiser Committee Reports, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    326.02
  - Volume IV-Domestic Research Crime, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    419.2
  - Volume V-Domestic Research Crime, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    419.3
  - Review of Congressional Hearings: Ad Hoc Committee on Urban Growth, October 15, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    328.04
  - U.S. Government Memorandum on Tax Reform Act (December 31), 1969 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    328.07
  - New Communities, 1969 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    327.30
  - Town and Country Planning Association: Evidence to the Property Advisory Group of the Department of the Environment, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 19)
    341.04
  - Selected Recent Housing and Urban Development (HUD)-Financed New Town Studies, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 20)
    327.06
  - Federalism in the Sixties A Ten Year Review-Chapter 1, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 21)
    328.10
  - U.S. Senate Report on New Towns, 1970s (Box 5, Folder 22)
    326.17
  - New Communities Development Committee (NCDC) Key Papers, 1970 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    335.02
  - Housing and Urban Development (HUD) News: The Tough Issues in an Urban Growth Policy-June 9, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    330.03